Guide to the Frank Altschul Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VIII: Organizations, 1908-1980
  - National Committee for a Free Europe--Radio Free Europe
    - Association Internationale de Droit Penal, 1950 (Box 165, Folder 14)
    - Committee II, 1950 (Box 166, Folder 1)
    - "Communist Manifesto," Draft of Altschul Radio Speech, undated (Box 166, Folder 2)
    - Crusade for Freedom, 1951 (Box 166, Folder 3)
    - Crosby, Jolen--Articles, 1951 (Box 166, Folder 4)
    - Desk "X"--General, 1950 (Box 166, Folder 5)
    - Directives--General, 1951 (Box 166, Folder 6)
    - Facilities and Schedules, 1950 (Box 166, Folder 7)
    - Fischer, George, 1951 (Box 166, Folder 8)
    - Gray, Gordon, 1950 (Box 166, Folder 9)
    - Gusten, Theodore J.H., 1951 (Box 166, Folder 10)
    - Hart, Mervin K., 1949 (Box 166, Folder 11)
    - Jackson, Wilson, 1950 (Box 166, Folder 12)
    - Kellr, Adolph, 1950 (Box 166, Folder 13)
    - Kempner, Fritz, 1950 (Box 166, Folder 14)
    - Korbel, Paul, 1951 (Box 166, Folder 15)
    - Lehman, Herbert H., 1950-1951 (Box 166, Folder 16)
    - Lewis, W.S., 1950 (Box 166, Folder 17)
    - Malik, Charles, 1950 (Box 166, Folder 18)
    - McCluney, Forrest, 1951 (Box 166, Folder 19)
    - Marshall, Charles B., 1950 (Box 166, Folder 20)
    - Memorandum, 1950 July 20 (Box 166, Folder 21)
    - Policy Guidance--Memorandum #1, undated (Box 166, Folder 22)
    - Policy Guidance--Washington Guidance, 1950 (Box 166, Folder 23)
    - Poole, Dewitt Clinton, 1950 (Box 166, Folder 24)
    - Poole Memorandum, 1950 (Box 166, Folder 25)
    - Press Clippings, 1949-1951 (Box 166, Folder 26)
    - Program Services Section, 1951 (Box 166, Folder 27)
    - Programs--General, 1951-1953 (Box 167, Folder 1)
    - Programs--Czechoslovakia Desk, 1952-1953 (Box 167, Folder 2)
    - Radio Committee Minutes, 1950 (Box 167, Folder 3)
    - Reports, 1950-1954 (Box 167, Folder 4)
    - Research and Information, 1951 (Box 167, Folder 5)
    - Research and Information, 1951(3 Folders) (Box 168, Folder 1)
    - Research and Information, "The Black Book," vol. I and II, 1951-1952 (Box 168, Folder 2)
    - Research and Publications, Service--Czechoslovakia Section, 1953-1954 (Box 168, Folder 3)
    - Research Program on USSR, 1952-1953 (Box 168, Folder 4)
    - Slansky Trial Transcript, 1952-1953 (Box 168, Folder 5)
    - Smith, Margaret Chase--Response to her "A Declaration of Conscience," 1950 (Box 169, Folder 1)
    - Smith, Warren Hunting, 1950-1951 (Box 169, Folder 2)
    - Staff--Correspondence to NY-RFE for Overbrook Farm, 1952 (Box 169, Folder 3)
    - Staff--Correspondence with Individuals Offering Service, 1952 (Box 169, Folder 4)
    - Sweetser, Arthur, 1950 (Box 169, Folder 5)
    - Voice of America, 1951 (Box 169, Folder 6)
    - Weld, Arthur, 1950 (Box 169, Folder 7)
    - Wheeler, Walter, 1950 (Box 169, Folder 8)
    - General Correspondence
      - Bulgaria, 1953-1954 (Box 169, Folder 9)
      - Bulgaria, Translations of Letters from Listeners, 1951 (Box 169, Folder 10)
      - Czechoslovakia, 1951-1953 (Box 169, Folder 11)
      - Czechoslovakia, Translations of Letters from Listeners, 1951 (Box 169, Folder 12)
      - Czechoslovakia, Reports, 1951-1955 (2 Folders) (Box 169, Folder 13 to 14)
      - Germany, 1952-1955 (Box 169, Folder 15)
      - Hungary, 1951-1957 (2 Folders) (Box 170, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Hungary--Translations of Letters from Listeners, 1951 (2 Folders (Box 170, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Poland--General Correspondence, 1953-1955 (2 Folders) (Box 170, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Poland--Translations of Letters from Listeners, 1951-1953 (3 Folders) (Box 171, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Romania, 1952-1954 (Box 171, Folder 4)
      - Romania--Translations of Letters from Listeners, 1951 (Box 171, Folder 5)
  - National Committee for Immigration Reform, 1964-1965 (Box 171, Folder 6)
  - National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy, 1957-1958 (Box 171, Folder 7)
  - National Committee on United States--China Relations, 1967-1969 (Box 171, Folder 8)
  - National Committee on United States--China Relations, 1971-1979 (Box 172, Folder 1)
  - National Committee to Uphold Constitutional Government, 1951 (Box 172, Folder 2)
  - National Council for Civic Responsibility, 1958-1965 (Box 172, Folder 3)
  - National Jeffersonian Democrats Declaration, 1960 (Box 172, Folder 4)
  - National Planning Association
    - General, 1960-1973 (4 Folders) (Box 172, Folder 5 to 8)
    - General, 1974-1979 (5 Folders) (Box 173, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1957 (Box 173, Folder 6)
    - Geiger, Theodore, 1950-1954 (Box 173, Folder 7)
    - Gold Standard
      - General, 1962 (Box 174, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 174, Folder 2)
      - Working Papers, 1962-1963 (Box 174, Folder 3)
      - Clippings, 1962-1964 (Box 174, Folder 4)
      - Pamphlets and Monographs, 1961-1963 (Box 174, Folder 5)
      - Meeting, 1963-1972 (3 Folders) (Box 174, Folder 6 to 8)
      - Pamphlets, 1950-1961 (Box 174, Folder 9)
      - Woodrow Wilson Foundation, Joint Study Group, 1952-1953 (Box 174, Folder 10)
  - National Strategy Information Center, Inc, 1971-1974 (Box 174, Folder 11)
  - The New Leader, 1952-1959 (Box 174, Folder 12)
  - The New School, General Correspondence, 1934-1976 (6 Folders) (Box 175, Folder 1 to 6)
  - The New School, Fundraising Campaign, 1944 (Box 175, Folder 7)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1952-1961 (Box 176, Folder 1)
  - New York Herald Tribune--Editorial by Frank Altschul, 1947-1975 (Box 176, Folder 2)
  - New York State Office for the Aging, 1967-1968 (Box 176, Folder 3)
  - The Newberry Library Association, 1965-1966 (Box 176, Folder 4)
  - The North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 1952-1956 (Box 176, Folder 5)
  - Pan American Society of the United Stated, Inc, 1953-1959 (Box 176, Folder 6)
  - The Pilgrims, 1953-1974 (Box 176, Folder 7)
  - Radio Corporation of American (RCA), 1946-1957 (Box 176, Folder 8)
  - Rand Corporation, 1955-1973 (Box 177, Folder 1)
  - Recording for the Blind, 1966-1975 (5 Folders) (Box 177, Folder 2 to 6)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1956-1957 (Box 177, Folder 7)
  - School of Advanced International Studies, 1966-1970 (2 Folders) (Box 177, Folder 8 to 9)
  - School of Advanced International Studies, 1966-1978 (3 Folders) (Box 178, Folder 1 to 3)
  - The Stamford Advocate, 1952-1977 (Box 178, Folder 4)
  - Stamford Community Chest, 1942-1949 (Box 178, Folder 5)
  - Stamford Forum for World Affairs, 1947-1963 (4 Folders) (Box 178, Folder 6 to 9)
  - Stamford Forum for World Affairs, 1947-1976 (8 Folders) (Box 179, Folder 1 to 8)
  - Stamford Forum for World Affairs--First Annual Altschul Award Dinner, 1978 (Box 179, Folder 9)
  - Stamford Hospital, 1949-1953 (2 Folders) (Box 179, Folder 10 to 11)
  - Stamford Hospital, 1954-1978 (6 Folders) (Box 180, Folder 1 to 6)
  - Stamford Hospital--General Correspondences, 1947-1967 (Box 180, Folder 7)
  - Stamford Hospital Recognition Dinner Scroll of Honor, 1965 November 17 (Box 201 Oversize, Folder 2)
  - Stamford Organizations--General, 1947 (Box 180, Folder 8)
  - Stamford League of Women Voters, 1947-1951 (Box 180, Folder 9)
  - Stamford Postwar Planning Council, 1943-1945 (Box 180, Folder 10)
  - Stamford Postwar Planning Council--Organization Charts, undated (Box 201 Oversize, Folder 4)
  - Stamford United Fund, 1954-1969 (Box 181, Folder 1)
  - United Jewish Appeal, 1949-1964 (Box 181, Folder 2)
  - United States War Department, 1915-1932 (3 Folders) (Box 181, Folder 3 to 5)
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation
    - 1943-1944 (3 Folders) (Box 181, Folder 6 to 8)
    - 1945-1970 (8 Folders) (Box 182, Folder 1 to 8)
    - Financial Statements, 1946 (Box 201 Oversize, Folder 5)
    - Acheson--Working Papers, 1953 (Box 183, Folder 1)
    - Acheson Award Correspondence, 1953 (Box 183, Folder 2)
    - Dinner, Award, Speeches, Working Papers, 1953 (Box 183, Folder 3)
    - Financial Statements, 1946-1949 (4 Folders) (Box 183, Folder 4 to 7)
    - Publications, 1953-1973 (Box 183, Folder 8)
  - Yale University
    - Correspondence, 1925-1959 (8 Folders) (Box 184, Folder 1 to 8)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1980 (8 Folders) (Box 185, Folder 1 to 8)
    - Alumni Association, 1950-1957 (Box 185, Folder 9)
    - Alumni Board, 1952-1973 ( 2 Folders) (Box 185, Folder 10 to 11)
    - Alumni Board Designating Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 186, Folder 1)
    - Alumni Class of 1908, 1963-1979 (Box 186, Folder 2)
    - Alumni Class of 1908 Overbrook Farm, 1962-1963 (Box 186, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Alumni Fund, 1947-1974 (Box 186, Folder 5)
    - Alumni Fund, Class of 1908, 1942-1962 (Box 186, Folder 6)
    - Alumni Sponsoring Committee, 1958 (Box 186, Folder 7)
    - Buckley, William F., Jr., "God and Man at Yale," Correspondence and Book, 1951 (Box 186, Folder 8 to 9)
    - Budget, 1950-1954 (Box 187, Folder 1)
    - Campaign for Yale, 1974-1977 (Box 187, Folder 2)
    - Challenge--Political Group, 1962-1967 (Box 187, Folder 3)
    - Clubs
      - Economics, 1927-1931 (Box 187, Folder 4)
      - Faculty, 1968-1973 (Box 187, Folder 5)
      - Yale Club of New York, 1968-1977 (Box 187, Folder 6)
      - Yale Club of Stamford, 1968-1976 (Box 187, Folder 7)
      - Yale Club of Stamford Meeting, 1973 (Box 187, Folder 8)
    - Committee on International Studies, 1960-1961 (Box 187, Folder 9)
    - Committee on Social Studies: Economics Department
      - Correspondence, 1950-1969 (4 Folders) (Box 187, Folder 10 to 13)
      - Meetings, 1972 (Box 188, Folder 1)
      - Reports and Working Papers, undated (Box 188, Folder 2)
      - Reports, 1974 (Box 188, Folder 3)
      - Human Relations Area Files
        - Correspondence, 1953-1960 (4 Folders) (Box 188, Folder 4 to 7)
        - Letters to Professors and Acknowledgements, 1953 (Box 188, Folder 8)
        - Report and Working Papers, undated (Box 188, Folder 9)
        - Reports, 1951-1959 (Box 188, Folder 10)
    - Council
      - Correspondence, 1949-1959 (6 Folders) (Box 189, Folder 1 to 6)
      - Correspondence, Altschul--President, 1955-1956 (Box 189, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, F.A. President--Congratulations, 1955-1958 (Box 189, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence to Chairmen of Committees, 1953 (Box 189, Folder 9)
      - Library Committee, undated (Box 189, Folder 10)
      - Meeting, 1955-1956 ( 2 Folders) (Box 189, Folder 11 to 12)
      - Meeting, 1955-1957 (3 Folders) (Box 190, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Memos, Reports, Minutes, 1949-1957 (5 Folders) (Box 190, Folder 4 to 8)
      - Personnel, 1952-1953 (Box 190, Folder 9)
      - Publications Committee, 1956-1960 (Box 190, Folder 10)
      - Report to President Griswold and the Committee on Endowment, 1955 March (Box 190, Folder 11)
      - Committee Reports (5 Folders) (Box 191, Folder 1 to 5)
      - Treasurer's and President's Reports, 1950-1953 (Box 191, Folder 6)
    - Development Fund, 1960-1976 (Box 191, Folder 7)
    - Dinners, 1934-1951 (Box 191, Folder 8)
    - Economic Growth Center Advisory Council, 1960-1978 (Box 191, Folder 9)
    - Economic Growth Center Advisory Council, 1960-1978 (4 Folders) (Box 192, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Gifts and Fellowships
      - Correspondence, 1923-80 (5 Folders) (Box 192, Folder 5 to 9)
      - Overbrook Prize, 1961 (Box 193, Folder 1)
      - Gifts--General, 1952-1970 (2 Folders) (Box 193, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Graduate Placement Bureau, 1929 (Box 193, Folder 4)
    - Honorary Degree--Correspondence, 1966-1967 (2 Folders) (Box 193, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Honorary Degree Committee, 1955-1957 (Box 193, Folder 7)
    - Institute of International Studies--General and Fundraising, 1942-1951 (2 Folders) (Box 193, Folder 8 to 9)
    - Library Correspondence, 1923-1925 (2 Folders) (Box 193, Folder 10 to 11)
    - Library Correspondence, 1925-1931 (6 Folders) (Box 194, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Library Correspondence, 1923-1980 (7 Folders) (Box 195, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Library Correspondence--Altschul Fund--Gifts, 1924-1951 (Box 195, Folder 8)
    - Library Correspondence--Altschul Fund--Gifts, 1924-1963 (2 Folders) (Box 196, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Library Correspondence--Thomas Mann Collection, 1937-1938 (Box 196, Folder 3)
    - Library Associates A-Z, 1920s-1930s ( 2 Folders) (Box 196, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Library Associates, 1924-1980 (3 Folders) (Box 196, Folder 6 to 8)
    - Library Associates Luncheon, 1941 (Box 197, Folder 1)
    - Library Associates Meeting, 1969 (Box 197, Folder 2)
    - Library Associates Fund, 1932-1932 (Box 197, Folder 3)
    - Medal--Letters of Congratulation, 1943 (Box 197, Folder 4)
    - Pierson College, 1933-1979 (7 Folders) (Box 197, Folder 5 to 11)
    - Pierson College--"John Hersey: Excerpts from an Address at His Instillation as Sixth Master of Pierson College," 1965 November 15 (Box 201 Oversize, Folder 6)
    - Publishing Association, 1925-1935 (Box 198, Folder 1)
    - Russia--Report, undated (Box 198, Folder 2)
    - School of Fine Arts, 1928-1951 (Box 198, Folder 3)
    - School of Medicine, 1939-1944 (Box 198, Folder 4)
    - Sociology, 1954-1955 (Box 198, Folder 5 to 7)
    - Steel Research Project, 1952 (Box 198, Folder 8)
    - Student's Petition Against Allied Aid, 1940 (Box 198, Folder 9)
    - Undergraduate Lecture Committee, 1958-1962 (Box 198, Folder 10)
    - Wolfers, Arnold, 1950-1951 (Box 198, Folder 11)
    - Yale-in-China, 1958-1965 (Box 198, Folder 12)
    - Yale Literary magazine, Slave, 1947-1949 (Box 198, Folder 13)
    - Yale Medal Committee, 1951-1956 (Box 198, Folder 14)
    - Yale Medal--Letters of Congratulations, 1954-1957 (Box 198, Folder 15)
    - Yale News/Yale Review, 1935-1949 (Box 199, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, circa 1970 (Box 199, Folder 2)
    - Pamphlets, 1958-1964 (Box 199, Folder 3)
    - Reports--General, 1953-1983 (Box 199, Folder 4)
    - Yale University Press
      - General, 1930-1962 (2 Folders) (Box 199, Folder 5 to 6)
      - General Correspondence, 1962-1967 (Box 199, Folder 7)
      - Rollins, Carl P.--Dinner Invitations, 1960 (Box 199, Folder 8)
      - Rollins, Carl P.--Fund Raising Correspondence, 1960-1974 (Box 199, Folder 9)
      - Rollins, Carl P.--General Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 199, Folder 10)